<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content"><channel><title>CodeCompletion.io</title><description>A description of CodeCompletion.io</description><link>https://codecompletion.io</link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 03:04:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 03:04:52 +0000</pubDate><ttl>250</ttl><atom:link href="https://codecompletion.io/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://codecompletion.io/live/2020/ep-2</guid><title>Episode 2 Live Stream</title><description>Watch the live stream for Episode 2 of Code Completion.</description><link>https://codecompletion.io/live/2020/ep-2</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://codecompletion.io/episodes/2020/ep-1</guid><title>Episode 1: File, New, New Project…</title><description>We discuss how to layout your UI using compositional layouts and diffable data sources, different ways to bring an iPhone UI to the iPad, and ways Apple could make the App Store a better place for both developers and users.</description><link>https://codecompletion.io/episodes/2020/ep-1</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to Code Completion! We are a group of iOS developers and educators hoping to share what we love most about development, Apple technology, and completing your code on this brand new show!</p><p>Follow us <a href="https://twitter.com/CodeCompletion">@CodeCompletion</a> on Twitter to hear about our upcoming livestreams, videos, and other content.</p><p>Be sure to also sign up to our monthly newsletter, where we will recap the topics we discussed, reveal the answers to <em>#CompleteTheCode</em>, and share even more things we learned in between episodes.</p><p>You are what makes this show possible, so please be sure to share this with your friends and family who are also interested in any part of the app development process.</p><h2>This Week's Topics</h2><ul><li>How to layout your UI using compositional layouts and diffable data sources.</li><li>Different ways to bring an iPhone UI to the iPad.</li><li>Ways Apple could make the App Store a better place for both developers and users.</li></ul><h2>#CompleteTheCode</h2><p>This week's <em>#CompleteTheCode</em>:</p><blockquote>Without using a variable as a flag, how can you skip to the next iteration of an outer loop, from inside an inner loop?</blockquote><pre><code class="language-swift">for row in rows {
    for column in columns {
        if column.shouldSkipToNextRow {
            // how do you get to the next row?
        }
    }
    finishUpRow(row)
}
</code></pre><p>Be sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=%23CompleteTheCode%20cc%2F%20%40CodeCompletion&original_referer=https%3A%2F%2Fcodecompletion.io">tweet us</a> with hashtag <em><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/CompleteTheCode">#CompleteTheCode</a></em> if you know the answer!</p><h2>Compiler Error</h2><ol><li>Known as the key with the apple logo, the command key has been represented by the unicode character known as <code>PLACE OF INTEREST SIGN</code> since the Apple III.</li></ol><ol start="2"><li>Used on many systems that are very different from Macs, the control key on Mac OS differentiates itself from the competition by using the <code>UP ARROWHEAD</code> unicode character rather than the abbreviation, bar, or traditional caret notations.</li></ol><ol start="3"><li>Located between the control and command keys on the keyboard, the option key is unoriginally called <code>OPTION KEY</code> in the unicode specification, but was also known as the “closed apple key” on Apple II series computers.</li></ol><ol start="4"><li>Despite being used on some of the earliest computers, the shift modifier on Apple keyboards simply uses the <code>UPWARDS WHITE ARROW</code> character, an approximation of the standardized Level 2 Select key’s original symbol.</li></ol><details><summary>Compilation Results</summary><div class="details">

<p>Ben went first, followed by Spencer. Let's check how they did!</p>

<blockquote>4. Despite being used on some of the earliest computers, the shift modifier on Apple keyboards simply uses the <code>UPWARDS WHITE ARROW</code> character, an approximation of the standardized Level 2 Select key’s original symbol.</blockquote>

<p>Everyone thought this was true, and it is indeed a <em>code completion</em>! <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shift_key">Learn More →</a></p>

<blockquote>3. Located between the control and command keys on the keyboard, the option key is unoriginally called <code>OPTION KEY</code> in the unicode specification, but was also known as the “closed apple key” on Apple II series computers.</blockquote>

<p>Spencer thought this was true, while Ben thought this was the error, but it was also a <em>code compeltion</em>! <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Control_key">Learn More →</a></p>

<blockquote>2. Used on many systems that are very different from Macs, the control key on Mac OS differentiates itself from the competition by using the <code>UP ARROWHEAD</code> unicode character rather than the abbreviation, bar, or traditional caret notations.</blockquote>

<p>Spencer thought this was the error, but it was also a <em>code compeltion</em>! <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Option_key">Learn More →</a></p>

<p>Which means that…</p>

<blockquote>1. Known as the key with the apple logo, the command key has been represented by the unicode character known as <code>PLACE OF INTEREST SIGN</code> since the Macintosh introduced in 1984, though the command key itself was present on the Apple III introduced in 1980, but it was represented by an open Apple logo instead.</blockquote>

<p>is in fact the <strong>compiler error</strong>! <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Option_key">Learn More →</a></p>

</div></details><h2>Sponsor</h2><p>This week's episode of Code Completion is brought to you by <a href="https://apps.apple.com/app/apple-store/id1448552588?pt=14724&ct=CodeCompletion1&mt=8">Huuungry</a>. <a href="https://apps.apple.com/app/apple-store/id1448552588?pt=14724&ct=CodeCompletion1&mt=8">Click here</a> or search for Huuungry on the iOS App Store today to give it a try.</p>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>